Neural Networks are one of
神经网络是当今
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
the most powerful learning algorithms that we have today.
最强大的学习算法之一
In this, and in the
在本节课视频
next few videos, I'd like to
和后面几次课程中
start talking about a learning
我将开始讲述一种
algorithm for fitting the parameters
在给定训练集下
of the neural network given the training set.
为神经网络拟合参数的学习算法
As for the discussion of most
正如我们讨论大多数
of the learning algorithms, we're going
学习算法一样
to begin by talking about the
我们准备从拟合神经网络参数的
cost function for fitting the parameters of the network.
代价函数开始讲起
I'm going to focus
我准备重点讲解
on the application of neural
神经网络在分类问题
networks to classification problems.
中的应用
So, suppose we have a
假设我们有一个如左边所示的
network like that shown on the left.
神经网络结构
And suppose we have a training
然后假设我们有一个
set like this of this of
像这样的训练集
Xi, Yi pairs of m training examples.
m个训练样本x(i) y(i)
I'm going to use upper case
我用大写字母 L
L to denote the
来表示
total number of layers in this network.
这个神经网络结构的总层数
So, for the network shown
所以 对于左边的网络结构
on the left, we would have
我们得到
capital L equals 4.
L等于4
And, I'm going to use
然后我准备用
s subscript L, to denote
sl表示
the number of units, that is
第L层的单元的数量
a number of neurons, not counting
也就是神经元的数量
the bias unit in layer L of the network.
这其中不包括L层的偏差单元
So, for example, we would
比如说
have a S1 which
我们得到s1 也就是输入层
is the input layer equals S3 unit,
是等于3的单元
S2 in my example is five units.
s2在这个例子里等于5个单位
And the output layer S4.
然后输出层s4
Which is also equals SL, because capital L is equal to four.
也就是sl 因为L本身等于4
The output layer in my
在左边这个例子中输出层
example in the left has four units.
有4个单位
We're going to consider two types of classification problems.
我们将会讨论两种分类问题
The first is binary classification,
第一种是二元分类
where the labels y are either zero or one.
在这里y只能等于0或1
In this case, we would have one output unit.
在这个例子中 我们有一个输出单元
So, this neural network on top
上面这个神经网络的有四个输出单元
has four output units, but if
但是如果我们
we had binary classification, we would
用二元分类的话
have only one output unit
我们就只能有一个输出结果
that computes h of x.
也就是计算出来的h(x)
And the outputs of the
神经网络的输出结果
neural network would be h
h(x)就会是
of x is going to be a real number.
一个实数
And in this case the number
在这类问题里
of output units, SL, where
输出单元的个数 sl
L is again the index
L同样代表最后一层的序号
of the final layer because that's
因为这就是我们
the number of layers we have in the network.
在这个网络结构中的层数
So the number of units we
所以我们在输出层的单元数目
have in the output layer is going to be equal to one.
就将是1
In this case, to simplify notation
在这类问题里 为了简化记法
later, I'm also going to set k equals 1.
我会把K设为1
So, you can think of k as
这样你可以把K看作
also denoting the number
输出层的
of units in the output layer.
单元数目
The second type of classification problem
我们要考虑的第二类分类问题
we'll consider will be multiclass classification
就是多类别的分类问题
problem where we may have k distinct classes.
也就是会有K个不同的类
So, our early example, I
比如说
had this representation for y
如果我们有四类的话
if we have four classes and
我们就用这样的表达形式来代表y
in this case, we would have caps lock K
在这类问题里 我们就会有K个输出单元
output units and our hypotheses
我们的假设输出
will output vectors that are K dimensional.
就是一个K维向量
And the number of output units
输出单元的个数
will be equal to K.
就等于K
And usually we will have
通常这类问题里
K greater than or equal
我们都有K大于
to three in this case, because
或等于3
if we had two classes then,
因为如果只有两个类别
you know, we don't need to
我们就不需要
use the one versus all method.
使用这种一对多的方法
We need to use the one versus
我们只有在K大于
all method only if we
或者等于3个类的时候
have K greater than or
才会使用这种
equal to three classes so we
一对多的方法
only have two classes we will
因为如果只有两个类别
need to use only one output unit.
我们就只需要一个输出单元就可以了
Now, let's define the cost function for our cost function for our neural network.
现在我们来为神经网络定义代价函数
The cost function we use for
我们在神经网络里
the neural network is going to
使用的代价函数
be a generalization of the
应该是逻辑回归里
one that we use for logistic
使用的代价函数的一般化形式
regression.  For logistic regression,
对于逻辑回归而言
we used to minimize the
我们通常使代价函数 J(θ)
cost function j of theta
最小化
that was minus 1 over
也就是-1/m
m of this cost function
乘以后面这个代价函数
and then plus this extra regularization
然后再加上这个额外正则化项
term here, where this was
这里是一个
a sum from j equals
j从1到n的求和形式
1 through n, because we
因为我们
did not regularize the bias term theta zero.
并没有把偏差项 0正则化
For a neural network our cost
对于一个神经网络来说
function is going to be a generalization of this.
我们的代价函数是这个式子的一般化形式
Where instead of having basically
这里不再是仅有一个
just one logistic regression output
逻辑回归输出单元
unit, we may instead have K of them.
取而代之的是K个
So here's our cost function.
所以这是我们的代价函数
Neural network now outputs vectors
神经网络现在输出了
in RK where K might
在K维的向量
be equal to 1 if we
这里K可以取到1 也就是
have the binary classification problem.
原来的二元分类问题
I'm going to use this notation,
我准备用这样一个记法
h of x subscript i, to denote the ith output.
h(x)带下标i 来表示第i个输出
That is h of x is a K dimensional vector.
也就是h(x)是一个K维向量
And so this subscript i just
下标 i 表示
selects out the ith element
选择了神经网络输出向量的
of the vector that is output by my neural network.
第i个元素
My cost function, j of
我的代价函数
theta is now going
J(θ) 将成为下面这样的形式
to be the following is minus one
-1/m乘以
over m of a sum
一个类似于我们在
of a similar term to what
逻辑回归里所用的
we have in logistic regression. Except that
求和项
we have this sum from K
除了这里我们求的是
equals one through K.  The
k从1到K的所有和
summation is basically a
这个求和项主要是
sum over my K output unit.
K个输出单元的求和
So, if I have four upper units.
所以如果我有四个输出单元
That is the final layer of my
也就是我的神经网络最后一层
neural network has four output
有四个输出单元
units then this sum
那么这个求和就是
from, this is a sum from
这个求和项就是
K equals one through four
求k等于从1到4的
of basically the logistic regression algorithms
每一个的逻辑回归算法的代价函数
cost function but summing
然后按四次输出的顺序
that cost function over each
依次把这些代价函数
of my four output units in turn.
加起来
And so, you notice
所以你会特别注意到
in particular that this applies
这个求和符号应用于
to YK, HK, because
yk和hk  因为
we're basically taking the K
我们主要是讨论
upper unit and comparing that
K个输出单元
to the value of YK, which
并且把它和yk的值相比
is you know, which is
yk的值就是
that one of those vectors
这些向量里表示
to say what cause it should be.
它应当属于哪个类别的量
And finally, the second term
最后 这里的第二项
here is the regularization
这就是类似于我们在逻辑回归里所用的
term similar to what we had for logistic regression.
正则化项
This summation terms looks really
这个求和项看起来
complicated and always doing
确实非常复杂
is a summing over these terms,
它所做的就是把这些项全部相加
theta j i l for
也就是对所有i j和l
all values of i j
的θji的值都相加
and l.  Except that we
正如我们在逻辑回归里一样
don't sum over the terms
这里要除去那些对应于偏差值的项
corresponding to these bias values
那些项我们是不加进去的
like we had for logistic progression.
Concretely, we don't sum
具体地说 我们不把
over the terms corresponding
那些对于i等于0的项
to where i is equal to zero.
加入其中
So, that is because
这是因为
when we are computing the activation
当我们计算神经元的激励值时
of the neuron, we have terms
我们会有这些项
like these, you know theta, i0
θi0
plus theta, i1,
加上θi1
x1 plus, and
乘以x1 再加上 等等等等
so on, where I guess
这里我认为
we could have a 2 there
我们可以加上2的上标
if this is the first hidden layer,
如果这是第一个隐含层的话
and so the values with
所以这些带0的项
the 0 there at that corresponds to
something that multiplies into an
对应于乘进去了
x0 or an a0 and
x0 或者是a0什么的
so, this is kind of like
这就是一个类似于
a bias unit and by
偏差单元的项
analogy to what we were
类比于我们在做
doing for logistic progression, we won't
逻辑回归的时候
sum over those terms in
我们就不应该把这些项
our regularization term because we
加入到正规化项里去
don't want to regularize them and
因为我们并不想正规化这些项
string the values 0.
并把这些项设定为0
But this is just one possible convention
但这只是一个合理的规定
and even if you were
即使我们真的把他们加进去了
to sum over, you know, i equals 0 up
也就是i从0加到sL
to SL, it will work
这依然成立
about the same and it doesn't make a big difference.
并且不会有大的差异
But maybe this convention
但是这个"不把偏差项正规化"
of not regularizing the bias
的规定可能只是会
term is just slightly more common.
更常见一些
So, that's the cost function
好了 这就是我们准备
we're going to use to fill on your own network.
应用于神经网络的代价函数
In the next video, we'll start
在下一个视频中
to talk about an algorithm for
我会开始讲解一个算法
trying to optimize the cost function.
来最优化这个代价函数